[
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, what news article did George Orr read on the subway?",
    "a": "\"NEW RESTAURANT OPENS IN DOWNTOWN\"",
    "b": "\"LOCAL SPORTS TEAM WINS CHAMPIONSHIP\"",
    "c": "\"WEATHER FORECAST FOR THE WEEK\"",
    "d": "\"CELEBRITY COUPLE BREAKS UP\"",
    "e": "\"BIG A-l STRIKE NEAR AFGHAN BORDER\"",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, why does George Orr say he stays in Portland?",
    "a": "He has a successful career there.",
    "b": "He loves the natural beauty.",
    "c": "He is afraid of the Mafia.",
    "d": "He is too poor to move.",
    "e": "He has always lived there.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, how does Dr. Haber act towards George Orr?",
    "a": "suspicious",
    "b": "disinterested",
    "c": "indifferent",
    "d": "genial",
    "e": "hostile",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, during his second session with Dr. Haber, George Orr dreams about",
    "a": "Mount Hood erupting",
    "b": "a horse defecating",
    "c": "an alien invasion",
    "d": "a large avalanche",
    "e": "Dr. Haber attacking him",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, Haber recommends that Orr should",
    "a": "avoid dreaming altogether",
    "b": "take a leave of absence from work",
    "c": "travel to the wilderness",
    "d": "rely solely on chemical stimulation",
    "e": "use and employ his mental powers",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, how has Orr's use of narcotics and pep pills affected him?",
    "a": "It has improved his ability to work.",
    "b": "It has made it impossible for him to dream.",
    "c": "It has improved his mental powers",
    "d": "It has left him emotionally off-balance",
    "e": "It has made him feel invincible",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, what does Orr ask Haber to do for him?",
    "a": "To teach him how to lucid dream",
    "b": "To prescribe him a new sleeping routine",
    "c": "To give him a new prescription for drugs",
    "d": "To give him a posthypnotic suggestion not to dream effectively",
    "e": "To analyze his daydreams",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, which type of daydream does Haber say he frequently has?",
    "a": "South Sea Island type daydreams",
    "b": "Messiah dreams, do-gooder dreams",
    "c": "Sado-masochist daydreams",
    "d": "Romantic fantasies of adolescence",
    "e": "Noble-suffering-martyr type daydreams",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, Dr. Haber tells Orr that, as a patient, he is",
    "a": "happy and joyful",
    "b": "generous and kind",
    "c": "angry and hostile",
    "d": "quiet and peaceful",
    "e": "intelligent and cooperative",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, what luxury does Orr wish he could afford?",
    "a": "a houseboat on a river",
    "b": "a private island retreat",
    "c": "a private pool",
    "d": "a beachfront villa",
    "e": "a cabin in the wilderness",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, how does Orr feel after having an effective dream?",
    "a": "energized and refreshed",
    "b": "broken and abraded",
    "c": "frightened and furious",
    "d": "content and fulfilled",
    "e": "confused and disoriented",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, what was the effective part of Orr’s final dream?",
    "a": "the appearance of Kennedy",
    "b": "the end of Orr’s anxiety",
    "c": "the presence of Haber",
    "d": "the stopping of the rain",
    "e": "the change of location",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, why was the Willamette not concreted over like other creeks and streams in the city?",
    "a": "It allowed Portland to be a port city.",
    "b": "It was too large to be concreted over.",
    "c": "The city government lacked the resources to concrete over it.",
    "d": "It was protected by strict environmental regulations.",
    "e": "It was important to the local wildlife.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, what has puzzled Orr regarding dreams?",
    "a": "why most dreams cannot be consciously recalled",
    "b": "why dreams are often nonsensical",
    "c": "what the purpose of dreams is",
    "d": "Whether other animals dream",
    "e": "why some dreams are more vivid than others",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 3, where does Orr live?",
    "a": "in a studio apartment",
    "b": "in a three-bedroom house",
    "c": "in a hotel",
    "d": "on a houseboat",
    "e": "in a shack",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a feature of the parking structure described at the beginning of Chapter 4?",
    "a": "It was once a high-rise building",
    "b": "It has a curved façade",
    "c": "It has a rooftop garden",
    "d": "It still smells of gasoline fumes",
    "e": "It was designed by a famous architect",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, how does Miss Lelache see herself?",
    "a": "as a victim",
    "b": "as a poisonous spider",
    "c": "as an ambitious lawyer",
    "d": "as a mentor",
    "e": "as a friendly coworker",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, how does Miss Lelache see George Orr?",
    "a": "confident and assertive",
    "b": "witty and charming",
    "c": "strong and muscular",
    "d": "tall and imposing",
    "e": "fragile and meek",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, which types of rights does George Orr believe that Dr. Haber is violating?",
    "a": "political",
    "b": "civil",
    "c": "privacy",
    "d": "social",
    "e": "economic",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, Miss Lelache is a(n)",
    "a": "doctor",
    "b": "engineer",
    "c": "accountant",
    "d": "lawyer",
    "e": "teacher",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, what is George Orr’s attitude toward his situation?",
    "a": "angry and confrontational",
    "b": "hopeless and depressed",
    "c": "confident and optimistic",
    "d": "uncertain and confused",
    "e": "desperate and resigned",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, what does George Orr think about Dr. Haber’s motives?",
    "a": "He means well.",
    "b": "He is twisted.",
    "c": "He is evil.",
    "d": "He is megalomaniacal.",
    "e": "He is a mad scientist.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, what does George Orr say he wants from his visits to Dr. Haber?",
    "a": "to receive better drugs",
    "b": "to be cured",
    "c": "to increase his power",
    "d": "to regain his job",
    "e": "to improve the world",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, how does Miss Lelache feel about George Orr’s story?",
    "a": "skeptical",
    "b": "admiring",
    "c": "sympathetic",
    "d": "confused",
    "e": "amused",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, how does George Orr obtain a cabin in the wilderness?",
    "a": "He buys it from a friend.",
    "b": "He inherits it from a relative.",
    "c": "He dreams it into existence.",
    "d": "He finds it unattended.",
    "e": "He wins it in a lottery.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, which type of animal does George Orr use to illustrate his ability to change the order of nature?",
    "a": "red iguana",
    "b": "purple parakeet",
    "c": "yellow snake",
    "d": "green elephant",
    "e": "pink poodle",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, Miss Lelache agrees to observe a session with Dr. Haber in order to",
    "a": "get Dr. Haber into trouble",
    "b": "disprove Orr’s claims about effective dreaming",
    "c": "ensure that Orr’s civil rights are not violated",
    "d": "prove that the machine is experimental",
    "e": "help cure Orr’s ability to dream effectively",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, why does George Orr say he objects to Dr. Haber's treatment?",
    "a": "The treatment is physically painful.",
    "b": "The dreams are morally repugnant.",
    "c": "The machine is causing him physical harm.",
    "d": "Dr. Haber’s treatment is not effective.",
    "e": "He is being used as an instrument without his consent.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Lathe of Heaven, what does Miss Lelache suggest to George Orr after their first meeting?",
    "a": "getting a HEW order to investigate",
    "b": "stopping his drug use",
    "c": "destroying the machine",
    "d": "accusing Dr. Haber of misconduct",
    "e": "asking Dr. Haber for his cooperation",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 4, how does George Orr describe the purpose of the Augmentor?",
    "a": "to intensify the dream-state",
    "b": "to stop dreaming",
    "c": "to analyze dreams",
    "d": "to induce hypnosis",
    "e": "to change reality",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  }
]

